Chris Higgins

chris@chigs.me | (815) 761-9175 | http://chigstuff.com | Chicago, IL

Summary

Seven years of experience working in an information technology position, a Master's of Science in Information Systems, and a strong passion for both offensive and defensive information security. Offensive Security Certified Professional with interests in penetration testing, reverse engineering, and malware analysis.

Professional Experience

Uptake

Security Analyst Chicago, IL January 2017 - Present

Blue team security analyst protecting Uptake's data and employees from outsider and insider threats. The team I am a part of utilizes various SIEM components, threat intelligence, vulnerability management, employee training, and intrusion detection/prevention to keep our network and people safe. Also helped develop and test technical recruitment challenge provided by the company.

CAS-IT: Training & Advanced Projects

Lead Application Developer & Server Administrator Illinois State University, Normal, IL July 2013 - January 2017

Currently Lead Application Developer and part of the Server Administration team at CAS-IT. Duties include creating, modifying, and maintaining various applications that are required by both the College of Arts and Sciences and its faculty and staff. Our supported applications are a combination of home built, open source, and third party cloud services. Primary languages used include C#, PHP, Python, SQL, and Powershell. My server team responsibilities include managing all of our web servers and database servers keeping everything with a respectable uptime and great performance and maintaining strong security standards. Helped manage a team of student and intern developers.

CAS-IT: Training & Advanced Projects

Student Developer Illinois State University, Normal, IL October 2009 – June 2013

Created and updated various websites for the departments and faculty for the College of Arts and Sciences at Illinois State University. Most work was done with HTML, CSS, Javascript, ASP.NET, C#, and Python with tools such as Adobe Dreamweaver and Microsoft Visual Studio. Also performed work creating and editing graphics with Adobe Photoshop, helped faculty with survey creation using Select Survey, provided help for faculty that use our technologies and web assistance, and worked with various groups across campus for University wide projects.

Education

Illinois State University

M.S., Information Systems
May 2016
Focus on Network & Security
Management

Illinois State University
B.S., Information Technology
May 2013

Focus on Web Application Development

Certifications

Offensive Security Certified Professional (OSCP)

April 2015

ITIL Foundations
June 2014

Relevant Skills

Exploit development; reverse engineering; web and application development; Linux and Windows administration; Metasploit development; SOC operations;